# **Mallory McBee**

440-319-6684

501 N Negley Ave Pittsburgh, PA 15206

https://malmcb.github.io

#### **PROFILE**

mallorymcbee@gmail.com Recent graduate from a Master's degree program in Data Science looking to start my career. Passionate about learning and improving daily life with decision science. I have 5 years of experience working in the healthcare field where I worked in a laboratory conducting high complexity testing.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **Medical Laboratory Scientist**

UPMC Shadyside, Pittsburgh, PA — 2021 - Present

Performed hematology, chemistry, coagulation, urinalysis, and PCR testing in an urban hospital laboratory as well as its outpatient cancer center. Answered questions from other hospital staff regarding testing requirements and results. Assisted with bone marrow biopsies at the patient's bedside.

# **Medical Laboratory Scientist**

Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, OH — 2017-2020

Was responsible for monitoring turn around time data for coagulation tests in patient's who were suspected of having a stroke. Compiled 3 years worth of data on quality incident reports in the lab and analyzed the trends in Excel to create a better incident reporting system. Performed hematology, coagulation, and urinalysis tests for patients at the Main Campus building for Cleveland Clinic.

## **Resident Assistant**

West Virginia University, Morgantown, WV — 2014-2016

Helped first year university students transition into on-campus housing and adapt to college life. Planned and implemented different education and social programs for the dormitory.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Eastern University, St Davids, PA — Master of Science in Data Science

Capstone project was analysis of census data in Allegheny County and building a classification model to determine which factors most influence food desert status.

West Virginia University, Morgantown, WV — Bachelor of Science in Medical **Laboratory Science** 

### **SKILLS**

Python, SQL, R, HTML/CSS, Tableau, Qlik, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Scikitlearn, Seaborn, Machine learning, data analysis, feature engineering